It was an age of war.
Relying only on his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not a modern samurai.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION RESULTS
DETAILED RESULTS
URIC ACID
D
D: RE-TEST REQUIRED
Hey.
Yes?
It says I need a re-test.
What should I do?
Oh, where?
Oh, you're right.
I see.
What do you mean?
You sound like you don't care.
You'll be fine with
early diagnosis and treatment.
After a re-test, it often turns out
that nothing is wrong.
I re-tested soon after that.
The results will be out today.
I have to think about
the worst-case scenario.
My will, inheritance...
I need a lawyer for that, right?
No!
I don't want to die.
I'm only 60!
Mr. Kasumi.
Mr. Takeshi Kasumi.
-This is it.
-Mr. Kasumi, this way please.
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
UMBRELLAS AT THE DINNER COUNTER
Hello.
I'm okay! There's nothing wrong!
That's great!
Let's do something special
and eat out tonight!
Sorry.
I'm going to my
yoga friend's birthday party.
Oh, really.
Too bad.
Don't drink too much.
I won't.
Bye.
That being said...
I've gotten doctor's approval.
I'm drinking today!
I doubt there's any bar open this early.
IZAKAYA YAMACHAN
This place is open.
It looks quite old.
And pretty busy.
Okay, I'm going to try it!
Welcome back!
-This way, please!
-Okay.
I wish I could reply, "Good to be back."
The weekly tabloid beat me again.
What?
The minister's money scandal.
That makes me so mad.
-It's always the same--
-Ice!
Yes! Hold on one second.
I can't stand it.
-Here you go.
-Okay.
I really like it.
Cartilage and tongue.
Sure.
It's been a while
since I've been to
a traditional izakaya like this.
Okay, what would you like?
Draft beer.
Large? Medium?
Large.
Sure!
Here, large draft!
Thanks.
I'd been fighting the urge to drink
ever since I knew I had to get retested.
This is amazing!
This is the best!
KASANE - STEWED TOFU, $6
At this bar...
they call stewed tofu...
kasane.
Excuse me.
I'll have one order of kasane.
Sure.
It means stewed tofu...
with stewed offal layered on top.
Onion instead of scallion.
And so much of it.
Here, kasane.
Thanks.
This is so good!
This is real bar food.
It tastes like it's bad for my health.
But that's what...
makes it so good!
An onion topping.
What a great idea.
Did something good happen?
You were smiling just now.
No. Well, actually...
I saw the doctor today
to get my test results.
All clear.
Oh, that's great!
So, I'm celebrating.
Drink as much as you want, then!
Health is important.
Yes, I really think so.
-Thanks.
-Check, please.
You're leaving early today.
The forecast said
there will be heavy rain today.
That means we can do that today.
I'll pass.
Bye.
Thank you.
Bye, enjoy.
Okay, thanks.
Welcome back!
-Hi!
-Hello again.
Welcome back!
They must be regulars.
-Two beers!
-Coming up!
Would you like another?
Well...
Sake...
-and cubed tuna.
-Okay.
Here, cubed tuna.
Nice colors.
It looks good.
Can't there be someone...
who only does sales?
I don't understand.
It's so half-hearted.
Today again...
It's tough higher up.
That's why I say
I don't like things like that.
It's been bothering me. I don't get it.
What's the point?
What's wrong with them?
I really hate--
Actually, I think they hate us.
I want to ask...
Why won't the chief
give me the Kanto job?
That's because...
the chief has his plans.
This is already my third year.
I think you can handle it.
I know I can.
Sounds like me a long time ago.
-I know!
-You work hard...
No, I can't.
I just can't accept it.
I understand how you feel.
But the chief has his plans.
What?
What kind of plans?
I'm absolutely sure that
I can boost sales more than Hirata.
You don't know for sure.
I went on sales rounds with Hirata.
He's working really hard.
I really depend on him.
I still can't accept it!
I'm going to go directly
to the chief tomorrow!
I'm okay.
Sorry, sorry. I'm okay.
Listen to me...
I want to do something big soon.
I know.
I'm saying this for the company.
-I know.
-I'm working hard for the company.
I really am.
No one listens to me.
In my twenties...
-Let's keep going!
-...I was passionate about work
and had an irrational confidence.
Over the years,
as my responsibilities increased,
I learned how to cut corners
and compromise.
I'm doing it.
Those were the good old days.
I wanna hear his idea.
He's a really good guy.
Here, fried chicken.
Without sales,
nothing else will ever begin.
We're working hard, you know?
So, that's why...
I think it's better
if I talked to someone
in a department that understands us.
-That's right.
-I'm glad you understand.
I can't stop eating deep fried food.
Heartburn, go to hell!
Welcome back!
This way, please.
"Welcome back"?
This isn't my house.
Those people are so stupid.
-Potato shochu with water.
-Sure.
-Here you are.
-Good.
What is this? It's so weak!
He seems pretty drunk.
There's nothing good here.
Hey. How's the fried chicken?
It's good.
Is it? Then I'll have the same.
Sure.
I hate bars like this for commoners.
I only came in because it started raining.
I never go to run-down places like this.
Why stay just to complain?
If the company doesn't give work
to young people like me,
the company will become obsolete.
-That's true.
-Right! That's what I'm saying!
I've been listening to you, but...
you're being so immature.
People in management...
prioritize the company's risk.
Work goes to people with experience
instead of young guys who talk big.
Do you not understand that?
-That's why people these days are no good.
-So tactless.
-I should speak up.
-Hey!
How old are you?
Should I mind my own business?
-Twenty-five.
-Oh, big boy.
For a guy with such a cute face.
Do you seriously believe
that such shallow thinking
will make it in this world?
The world is filled with problems
because of fools like you!
Do you understand what I mean?
So cold!
You bastard!
What are you doing?!
Your head was hot, so I cooled it down.
What did you say?
Save the lectures...
for when you're sober!
Only the weak...
rely on alcohol.
Bastard!
You're just a lowly samurai...
Bastard! I'm going to kill you!
Now...
drink and talk...
all you like.
Yes!
Sake should be enjoyed.
-Right, miss?
-That's right!
And paying for your tab each time.
You got one on me.
For a company,
young and naive guys like you are--
Can you--
Stop?
What?
I think...
sake should be enjoyed.
Hey! The roof is leaking!
You're right!
Over here, too!
Hey, miss!
-The usual.
-Sure!
"The usual"?
Here we go!
It's here!
Okay, this is for the four over here.
Here you go.
This is for you two.
Here.
-For you, too.
-Okay.
I see.
This is what they meant by "the usual."
Okay.
One, two...
It looks nice!
Another problem solved.
What do you mean, solved?
You're so funny!
I apologize for my manners.
It's no problem.
Being drunk is no excuse
for being childish.
I'm sorry for crossing the line.
It's okay.
Actually...
I retired this year.
Me, too.
Really? Is that so!
Watching them...
Takes me back to my company days.
I couldn't help myself.
Then...
You must have been
a pretty bossy manager.
Yes. I was the most hated manager.
I guess run-down bars aren't so bad.
Delicious!
Thank you very much!
This is a drink...
I'll never forget.
Hey!
That burns!
Good.
Hey, miss!
Where's my fried chicken?
Oh, it's raining so you can't cook!
It's a little wet, but you can have
some of mine.
Wet chicken! No way...
We were drinking in the bar
while holding umbrellas!
I've never done that before!
It was so much fun!
One more!
Yes.
I need you to stay healthy forever. Okay?
Thank you.
Someday,
I'm going to take you to the bar
with the leaky roof.
On a day when it pours.
That would be great!
Thanks for the meal.
It's delicious.
So delicious! And it burns!
That makes my body burn!
Doesn't the rain get your butt wet?
No, it's the strangest thing...
Subtitle translation by
Hoday Stearns